

📞 +57 3218477149

Nicolás Rubio García

Data analyst

ABOUT

Political Science and Economics student, Data Analyst, and enthusiast of web programming. About to graduate as a political scientist, and looking forward to a Master's in Data Science. I have authored articles and participated as a speaker at national congresses, with experience in the development and management of research projects, as well as in the analysis and modeling of massive datasets.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Consultant

Corporación Programa Desarrollo para la Paz del Magdalena Centro, December 2023 - Present

- Collaboration in the design and implementation of the comprehensive monitoring and evaluation system for the Corporation.
- · Generation of accurate and relevant statistical inputs for the Management Report corresponding to the year 2023.
- Creation of detailed maps for regional characterization.

Freelance Data Analyst

Freelance, March 2023 - Present

- · Development of an innovative methodology to measure the performance of healthcare systems in Latin America.
- Analysis and modeling of data extracted from the GEIH 2022-2023.
- · Detailed characterization of various indicators to drive regional development in Magdalena Centro.

Political Science Intern - Data Analyst

Corporación Programa Desarrollo para la Paz del Magdalena Centro, June 2023 - December 2023

- · Comprehensive diagnosis and update of databases.
- · Thorough analysis and detailed evaluation of data.
- · Creation of executive reports synthesizing and effectively communicating findings.
- Development specialized documents for municipal characterization.

PORTFOLIO AND NETWORKS



LANGUAGES

English Spanish



CERTIFICATION

Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Certificate, 2023

Data cleaning and preprocessing - Outstanding Badge, 2023

Data Science Fundamentals - Outstanding Badge, 2023

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Political Science, 2019 - 2023 (Awaiting the graduation ceremony).

Bachelor's Degree in Economics, 2021 - Present.

Artificial Science and Intelligence Bootcamp, 2023 - Present.

Diploma in Programming Skills with Emphasis on Websites, 2022.

Diploma in Applied Statistics and Applied Econometrics, 2023

SKILLS

